很久很久以前，在一个非常遥远的星系…
《星球大战：新的希望》
在这个时候，内战连连
反抗军的飞船从秘密基地袭击邪恶的帝国军
并赢取了初次胜利
在这次战争中
反抗军的间谍窃取了帝国的终极武器「死星」的设计图
死星是一座武装太空站
威力足以摧毁一个星球
在邪恶的帝国军追捕下
莉娅公主急于将偷得的设计图护送回航
用它来解救她的人民，并且使整个银河系获得新生…
Did you hear that？
你听到了吗？
They shut down the main reactor.
他们毁坏了主反应堆
We'll be destroyed for sure.
我们肯定完蛋了
This is madness.
太疯狂了
We're doomed.
我们死定了
There'll be no escape for the princess this time.
公主这次无法脱身了
What's that？
那是什么？
R2-D2，where are you？
R2-D2，你在哪里？
At last！
总算找到你了
Where have you been？
你到哪里去了？
They're heading in this direction.
他们就要从这里过来了
What are we going to do？
我们该怎么办？
We'll be sent to the spice mines of Kessel…
我们会被送到开索的乱坟场…
smashed into who knows what！
被捣成碎片的！
Wait a minute。Where are you going？
等等，你要去哪里？
The Death Star plans are not in the main computer.
死星的设计图不在主计算机中
Where are those transmissions you intercepted？
你截取的那些信息到哪里去了？
What have you done with those plans？
你把那些设计图怎么了？
We intercepted no transmissions.
我们没有截取任何的信息
This is a consular ship.
这是一艘领事飞船
We're on a diplomatic mission.
我们在执行外交任务
If this is a consular ship…
如果这是领事飞船…
where is the ambassador？
那么大使在哪里？
Commander，tear this ship apart until you've found those plans…
指挥官，掘地三尺也要把那些设计图找出来
and bring me the passengers！I want them alive！
把乘客带来！要活的！
There's one。Set for stun.
那里有一个，设定为击晕模式
She'll be all right.
她没事的
Inform Lord Vader we have a prisoner.
报告维德勋爵，我们抓到了一个囚犯
Hey！You're not permitted in there。It's restricted.
嘿，这里是不允许进入的，是禁区
You'll be deactivated for sure.
你会失灵的
Don't you call me a mindless philosopher…
不要嫌我啰嗦…
you overweight glob of grease！
你不该去那里
Now come out before somebody sees you.
在别人看到你之前快出来吧
Secret mission？What plans？
秘密使命？什么计划？
What are you talking about？
你在说什么？
I'm not getting in there.
我不要进去
I'm going to regret this.
我一定会后悔的
There goes another one.
又来了一个
Hold your fire。There's no life forms.
别开火，没有生命体
It must have short-circuited.
里面一定是些铁家伙
That's funny。The damage doesn't look as bad from out here.
真奇怪，损坏从这里看不是那么严重
Are you sure this thing is safe？
你确定这里安全吗？
Oh.
哦
Darth Vader。Only you could be so bold.
达斯·维德，只有你才会这么的胡作非为
The Imperial Senate will not sit still for this.
帝国参议院不会对此坐视不理的
When they hear you've attacked a diplomatic…
当他们知道你攻击了外交…
Don't act so surprised，Your Highness.
不要装得这么惊讶，殿下
You weren't on any mercy mission this time.
你可不是在干什么好事
Several transmissions were beamed to this ship by rebel spies.
叛军的间谍向你们的飞船定向传输了若干信息
I want to know what happened to the plans they sent you.
我想知道他们发送给你的那些计划是怎么回事
I don't know what you're talking about.
我不知道你在说什么
I'm a member of the Imperial Senate…
我是帝国参议院的成员…
on a diplomatic mission to Alderaan.
去奥德兰执行一项外交任务
You are part of the Rebel Alliance and a traitor.
你是叛军的一员，帝国的叛徒
Take her away！
把她带走
Holding her is dangerous.
劫持她很危险
If word of this gets out…
如果事情传出去…
it could generate sympathy for the rebellion in the senate.
可能在参议院中会产生对叛军的怜悯
I've traced the rebel spies to her.
种种迹象表明叛军间谍在和她联系
Now she is my only link to finding their secret base.
现在只有通过她才能找到他们的秘密基地
She'll die before she'll tell you anything.
她死也不会说什么的
Leave that to me.
都交给我吧
Send a distress signal…
发出一个求救信号…
and then inform the senate that all aboard were killed.
然后告诉参议院所有船上的人都死了
Lord Vader，the battle station plans…
维德勋爵，死星的设计图…
are not aboard this ship…
不在这艘飞船上…
and no transmissions were made.
而且并没有以其他方式传送走
An escape pod was jettisoned during the fighting…
刚刚一个逃生舱在战斗中被扔出飞船
but no life forms were aboard.
但是没有发现里面有生命迹象
She must have hidden the plans in the escape pod.
她一定把计划藏在那个逃生舱了
Send a detachment down to retrieve them… See to it personally，Commander.
派一支部队去把它找回来，指挥官，在我个人看来
There'll be no one to stop us this time.
这次不会有任何人阻止我们
Yes，sir.
是，长官
How did we get into this mess？
我们怎么这么倒霉？
I really don't know how.
我真不知是怎么回事
We seem to be made to suffer.
似乎有人安排我们去受苦一样
It's our lot in life.
这就是我们的命运吧
I've got to rest before I fall apart.
我必须休息一下不然就要散架了
My joints are almost frozen.
我的关节就要冻结了
What a desolate place this is！
这里真是个荒无人烟的地方！
Where do you think you're going？
你以为你在往哪里走？
Well，I'm not going that way.
我才不往那里走呢
It's much too rocky.
那里太多岩石了
This way is much easier.
这边的看起来好走许多
What makes you think…
你怎么会觉得…
there are settlements over there？
那里会有住人的地方呢？
Don't get technical with me.
别和我谈什么技术
What mission？What are you talking about？
什么任务？你在说什么？
I've just about had enough of you.
我受够你了
Go that way.
你往那里走吧
You'll be malfunctioning within a day…
不到一天你就会失灵的…
you nearsighted scrap pile.
你这个目光短浅的废铜烂铁
And don't let me catch you following me begging for help…
而且别让我发现你跟着我祈求帮助
because you won't get it.
因为我是绝不会帮你的
No more adventures.
我不要冒险
I'm not going that way.
我不走那条路
That malfunctioning little twerp.
那个该死的蠢货
This is all his fault.
这都是他的错
He tricked me into going this way…
是他把我骗到这条路来的…
but he'll do no better.
但是他也不会好到哪里去
Wait！What's that？
等一下！那是什么？
A transport.
一个运输车
I'm saved！
我得救了
Over here！
在这里！
Hey！
嘿！
Help！Please help！
救命！请救救我！
R2？
R2-D2，it is you！It is you！
R2-D2，是你！是你！
Someone was in the pod.
逃生舱里曾经有人
The tracks go off in this direction.
是往这个方向走的
Look，sir，droids.
看，长官，是机器人
We stopped.
我们停下来了
Wake up！Wake up！
起来！起来！
We're doomed.
我们死定了
Do you think they'll melt us down？
你觉得他们会把我们镕了吗？
Don't shoot！Don't shoot！
别开枪！别开枪！
Will this never end？
什么时候才能结束呀？
All right，fine。Let's go.
好吧，我们走
Luke！Luke！
卢克！卢克！
Luke，tell Uncle if he gets a translator…
卢克，告诉你叔叔，如果他买一个会翻译的机器人
be sure it speaks Bocce.
一定要懂波西才行
Doesn't look like we have much of a choice，but I'll remind him.
我们看起来没有太多的选择，我会告诉他的
Yeah，we'll take that red one.
好，我就要那个红色的
No，not that one.
不，不是那个
I suppose you're programmed for etiquette and protocol.
我想你是被用于行使繁文缛节的
Protocol？Why，it's my primary function，sir.
什么意思？这是我的主要功能，先生
I am well-versed in all the customs…
我对于所有的风俗习惯都了如指掌…
I have no need for a protocol droid.
我不需要你这样的机器人
Of course you haven't，sir.
你当然不需要了，先生
Not in an environment such as this.
在这样的环境中是不需要的
That is why I have been programmed…
这就是为什么我已计划…
What I really need is a droid who understands…
我只需要一个机器人能够懂得…
the binary language of moisture vaporators.
水蒸气蒸发器的二进制语言
Vaporators？Sir，my first job was programming binary load lifters…
蒸发器？先生，我的首要任务是操纵二进制货物起重机…
very similar to your vaporators in most respects.
在各个方面都和你的蒸发器很类似
Can you speak Bocce？
你懂波西语吗？
Of course I can，sir。It's like a second language to me…
我当然懂了，先生，它就像是我的第二语言一样
Yeah，all right。Shut up。I'll take this one.
好吧，你闭嘴吧，我要这个了
Luke！
卢克！
Take these two over to the garage，will you？
把这两个带到仓库去，好吗？
I want them cleaned up before dinner.
在午饭前把它们洗干净
But I was going into Tosche Station…
但是我要去托西空间站呢
to pick up some power converters.
去拿一些电整流器
You can waste time with your friends…
只要把家里的事情做完
when your chores are done.
我随便你和你的朋友们怎么浪费时间
Now come on。Get to it.
现在快干活吧，把它搞好
All right。Come on.
好吧，来吧
And the red one。Come on.
还有那个红色的，过来！
Well，come on，red。Let's go.
嘿，快来，那个红色的，我们走
Uncle Owen！
欧文叔叔！
Yeah？
什么事？
This R2 unit has a bad motivator。Look.
这个R2的发动机坏了，看！
Hey，what are you trying to push on us？
嘿，看看你们卖给我们什么烂玩意！
Excuse me，sir…
打扰一下，先生…
but that R2 unit is in prime condition，a real bargain.
那个R2的情况非常好，绝对是笔好买卖
Uncle Owen，what about that one？
欧文叔叔，那个怎么样？
What about that blue one？
那个蓝色的如何？
We'll take that one.
我们要那个了
Take this away.
把它拿走
You'll be very pleased with that one，sir.
你一定会对他满意的，先生
He really is in first-class condition.
他的状态绝对是一流的
I've worked with him before.
我以前和他共事过
Here he comes.
他来了
O.K。Let's go.
好吧，我们走
Now，don't you forget this.
现在，你可不要忘了这事
Why I should stick my neck out for you…
为什么我要为你卖命
is quite beyond my capacity.
这可不是我该做的
Thank the maker！
感谢造物主！
This oil bath is going to feel so good.
油浴实在是太舒服了
I've got such a bad case of dust contamination…
沙土的侵蚀让我的情况很不好
I can barely move.
我都快不能动了
It just isn't fair.
太不公平了
Oh，Biggs is right.
诶，比格斯是对的
I'm never gonna get out of here.
我永远都不能离开这里
Is there anything I might do to help？
我可以帮上什么忙吗？
No。Not unless you can alter time…
你帮不了我，除非你能改变时间
speed up the harvest，or teleport me off this rock.
加快收获的速度，或者把我传送出这个乱石堆
I don't think so，sir.
恐怕我不能，先生
I'm only a droid…
我只是一个机器人
and not very knowledgeable about such things…
对于这方面的知识不太了解
not on this planet，anyway.
至少在这个星球上
As a matter of fact，I'm not even sure which planet I'm on.
事实上，我都不知道我在哪个星球上
Well，if there's a bright center to the universe…
嗯，如果宇宙中有一个明亮的中心的话
you're on the planet that it's farthest from.
你就在离它最远的那个星球上
I see，sir.
我明白了，先生
You can call me Luke.
你可以叫我卢克
I see，Sir Luke.
我明白，卢克先生
Ha ha.
哈哈
Just Luke.
只要卢克就行了
Oh… And I am C-3PO，human-cyborg relations.
哦…我是C-3PO仿人类机器人
This is my counterpart… R2-D2.
这是我的伙伴，R2-D2
Hello.
你好
You got a lot of carbon scoring.
你有很多碳化磨痕
Looks like you boys have seen a lot of action.
看起来你们两个参与了不少行动
With all we've been through…
经过了我们所经历的一切…
sometimes I'm amazed we're in as good condition as we are…
有时连我自己都很惊讶，我们居然能保持这么好的状态
what with the rebellion and all.
和反抗军他们在一起共事
You know of the rebellion against the Empire？！
你们认识对抗帝国的反抗军？
That's how we came to be in your service…
不然我们也不会被卖到你这里来…
if you take my meaning，sir.
如果你懂我的意思的话，先生
Have you been in many battles？
你们经历过很多战役吗？
Several，I think.
一些，我想
Actually，there's not much to tell.
事实上，我没有太多的要说
I'm not much more than an interpreter…
我只不过是一个翻译者…
and not very good at telling stories.
并不太善于说故事
Well，not at making them interesting，anyway.
嗯，确切地说不能把故事说得有趣些
Well，my little friend…
我的小朋友…
you got something jammed in here real good.
有个东西塞在这里了
Were you on a Starcruiser or…
你们到过帝国战舰或是…
Help me，Obi-Wan Kenobi。You're my only hope.
帮帮我，欧比旺·肯诺比，你是我唯一的希望
What's this？
这是什么
「What is what」？He asked you a question.
快回答，他在问你问题呢
What is that？
那是什么？
Help me，Obi-Wan Kenobi.
帮帮我，欧比旺·肯诺比
You're my only hope.
你是我唯一的希望
Help me，Obi-Wan Kenobi.
帮帮我，欧比旺·肯诺比
You're my only hope.
你是我唯一的希望
He says it's nothing，sir，merely a malfunction.
他说这什么都不是，先生，只是一次故障
Old data。Pay it no mind.
旧的数据，不要理它
Who is she？She's beautiful.
她是谁？她可真漂亮
I'm afraid I'm not quite sure，sir.
我不太清楚，先生
I think she was a passenger on our last voyage.
我想她是我们上次一旅途中的一名乘客
A person of some importance，I believe.
一个不重要的人，我认为
Our captain was attached…
我们的船长和…
Is there any more to this recording？
这个录像还有其他部分吗？
Behave yourself，R2.
表现一下自己呀，R2
You're going to get us into trouble.
你这样会给我们惹麻烦的
It's all right。You can trust him。He's our new master.
没事的，你可以信任他，他现在是我们的新主人
He says that he's the property of Obi-Wan Kenobi…
他说他属于附近的一个居民…
a resident of these parts…
名叫欧比旺·肯诺比…
and it's a private message for him.
而且这是给欧比旺的私人信息
Quite frankly，sir，I don't know what he's talking about.
坦白地说，先生，我并不知道他在说什么
Our last master was Captain Antilles.
我们上一个主人是安德烈斯船长
But with all we've been through…
但是经过一些事情以后…
this little R2 unit has become a bit eccentric.
这个小机器人变得有些古怪了
Obi-Wan Kenobi。I wonder if he means old Ben Kenobi.
欧比旺·肯诺比，我想会不会是说本·肯诺比
I beg your pardon，sir，but do you know what he's talking about？
请再说一边，先生，你知道他在说什么吗？
I don't know any Obi-Wan…
我不认识什么欧比旺…
but old Ben lives out beyond the Dune Sea.
本住在沙丘之海的那一头
He's kind of a strange old hermit.
他是一个奇怪的隐士
Help me，Obi-Wan Kenobi.
帮帮我，欧比旺·肯诺比
I wonder who she is.
我在想她是谁
Sounds like she's in trouble.
听起来她好像有麻烦
I better play back the whole thing.
我最好从头看一边
He says the restraining bolt…
他说限制螺栓…
has short-circuited his recording system.
把他的影像系统给短路了
He suggests that if you remove the bolt…
他建议如果你能把那个螺栓拿掉…
he might be able to play back the entire recording.
他可能可以为你播放全部的影像
Oh，yeah。Well…
哦，好吧…
I guess you're too small to run away on me…
我想你们两个是不能从我手里逃掉的
if I take this off.
如果我把它拿掉的话
OK…
好吧…
There you go.
好了
Wait a minute。Where'd she go？
等一下，她去那里了
Bring her back。Play back the entire message.
把她放出来，播放全部的影像！
「What message」？
「什么影像」？
The one you've just been playing！
你刚刚放的那个
The one you're carrying inside your rusty innards.
你这个修铁罐里面存着的
Luke！Luke！
卢克！卢克！
All right，I'll be right there，Aunt Beru.
好的，我马上就到，贝鲁阿姨
I'm sorry，sir…
对不起…
but he appears to have picked up a slight flutter.
他好像受到一点扰动
Here。See what you can do with him.
拿着，看看你能做些什么
I'll be right back.
我马上就回来
Just you reconsider playing that message for him.
你还是考虑一下是否播放给他看吧
No，I don't think he likes you at all.
我想他一点都不喜欢你
No，I don't like you，either.
我也不喜欢你
You know，I think that R2 unit we bought might have been stolen.
我觉得我们买来的R2机器人可能是偷来的
What makes you think that？
你怎么会这么想？
Well，I stumbled across a recording while I was cleaning him.
我在清洗他的时候无意中搞出一段录像
He says he belongs to someone called Obi-Wan Kenobi.
他说他属于一个叫欧比旺·肯诺比的人
I thought he might have meant old Ben.
我想他也许是在说本
Do you know what he's talking about？
你知道他说的是什么吗？
Mm-mm.
呃
I wonder if he's related to Ben.
我想他和本有关
That wizard's just a crazy old man.
那个巫师只是一个疯老头子
Tomorrow，I want you to take that R2 unit to Anchorhead…
明天你把那个R2带到锚头城那里去
and have its memory erased.
把他的内存清空
That'll be the end of it。It belongs to us now.
这样就结束了，他现在属于我们
But what if this Obi-Wan comes looking for him？
如果这个欧比旺来找他怎么办？
He won't.
他不会的
I don't think he exists any more.
我不认为他还活着
He died about the same time as your father.
他和你父亲差不多一个时候去世的
He knew my father？
他认识我的父亲？
I told you to forget it.
我告诉你忘了这件事
Your only concern is to prepare those new droids for tomorrow.
你现在需要考虑的是让这些新机器人明天开始干活
In the morning，I want them up there on the south ridge…
明天一早，我希望看到他们在南边的山头上
working on those condensers.
操纵那些压缩机
Yes，sir.
好的
I think those new droids are gonna work out fine.
我想那些机器人工作会顺利的
In fact，I，uh，was also thinking about our agreement…
事实上，我也在想我们协定
about me staying on another season？
有关我再呆一个季节的事情
And if these new droids do work out…
如果这些新的机器人能够工作…
I want to transmit my application to the academy this year.
我想今年就向学院发出申请
You mean the next semester before the harvest？
你是说在收获前的那个学期？
Sure。There's more than enough droids.
当然，这里的机器人绰绰有余
Harvest is when I need you the most.
收获是我最需要你的时候
It's only one season more.
只不过多干一个季度
This year we'll make enough on the harvest…
今年收获应该足够…
that I'll be able to hire more hands…
以后就可以雇佣更多的人手…
and then you can go to the academy next year.
这样，明年你就可以去学院了
You must understand I need you here，Luke.
你必须要理解，我这里很需要你，卢克
But it's a whole 'nother year！
但是，这又是一整年
Look，it's only one more season.
只是多干一个季度
Yeah，that's what you said when Biggs and Tank left.
是呀，比格斯和谭克离开的时候，你也是这么说的
Where are you going？
你要去哪里？
Looks like I'm going nowhere.
谁都看得出我哪都去不了
I have to go finish cleaning those droids.
我去把那些机器人洗完
Owen，he can't stay here forever.
欧文，他不能一直呆在这里
Most of his friends have gone.
大多数他的朋友都离开了
It means so much to him.
这对于他来说很重要
I'll make it up to him next year.
我明年会满足他的
I promise.
我保证
Luke's just not a farmer，Owen.
卢克可不只是一个农民，欧文
He has too much of his father in him.
他有太多的地方和他的父亲一样
That's what I'm afraid of.
这也正是我所担心的
Ooh！
哦！
What are you doing hiding back there？
你躲在后面干什么？
It wasn't my fault，sir。Please don't deactivate me.
这不是我的错，先生，求你不要关掉我
I told him not to go，but he's faulty，malfunctioning.
我告诉他不要走，但是他似乎出了故障
Kept babbling on about his mission.
一直都在嘀咕他的任务
Oh，no.
哦，不
That R2 unit has always been a problem.
那个R2机器人一直都有点问题
These astrodroids are getting quite out of hand.
这些航天机器人常常无法控制
Even I can't understand their logic at times.
即使是我也常常不能理解他的逻辑
How could I be so stupid？
他怎么能这么愚蠢？
He's nowhere in sight.
他不在视野之内
Blast it！
真该死！
Pardon me，sir，but couldn't we go after him？
对不起，先生，我们可以去追他吗？
It's too dangerous with all the Sandpeople around.
太危险了，到处都是沙人
We'll have to wait until morning.
我们必须要等到早晨
Luke！I'm shutting the power down.
卢克！我要关闭电源了
All right！I'll be there in a few minutes.
好的！我马上就回来
Boy，am I gonna get it.
我一定会把他找回来的
That little droid's going to cause me a lotta trouble.
那个小机器人会给我惹很多麻烦的
Oh，he excels at that，sir.
他最擅长这个了，先生
Come on.
来吧
Luke？
卢克？
Luke！
卢克！
Have you seen Luke this morning？
你今天早晨看到卢克了吗？
He said he had some things to do before he started today…
他说在今天开始干活前有些事要做…
so he left early.
所以他要早点走
Did he take those two new droids with him？
他把那两个新机器人也带上了？
I think so.
我想是的
Well，he better have those units in the south range…
好吧，他最好在中午之前把那两个机器人修好
repaired by midday，or there'll be hell to pay.
送到南边的山头去，不然那里就要多花很多钱了
Lookit，there's a droid on the scanner.
看，在扫描器上有一个机器人
Dead ahead.
直向前
It might be our little R2 unit。Hit the accelerator！
可能是我们的R2机器人，按加速器！
Hey，whoa！Where do you think you're going？
嘿，停下！你要去哪里？
Master Luke is your rightful owner now.
卢克主人现在是你的合法拥有者
We'll have no more of this Obi-Wan Kenobi gibberish.
不要再说什么欧比旺·肯诺比之类的东西
And don't talk to me of your mission，either.
也不要再和我说什么你的任务
You're fortunate he doesn't blast you…
你该感到很幸运
into a million pieces right here！
他没有向你射击把你打成碎片
No。It's all right，but I think we'd better go.
不，没事的，但是我想我们最好还是走吧
What's wrong with him now？
他现在又怎么了？
There are several creatures approaching from the southeast.
有若干生物从东南方向向我们逼近
Sandpeople，or worse.
沙人，或是更糟
Come on。Let's go have a look.
来，我们去看一看
Come on！
来呀！
Well，there are two Banthas down there…
下面有两头本莎…
but I don't see any… Wait a second.
但是没看到…等一下
They're Sandpeople，all right.
是沙人，没错
I can see one of them now.
我能看到他们其中一个
Hello，there.
你好啊
Come here，my little friend。Don't be afraid.
过来，我的小朋友，不要害怕
Oh，don't worry。He'll be all right.
别担心，他没事的
Rest easy，son。You've had a busy day.
你没事了，小伙子，你今天似乎很忙呀
You're fortunate to be all in one piece.
你很幸运你还是一整块
Ben？
本？
Ben Kenobi？
本·肯诺比？
Boy，am I glad to see you.
伙计，我很高兴见到你
The Jundland Wastes are not to be traveled lightly.
到这里来应该多带些武器
Tell me，young Luke…
告诉我，年轻的卢克…
what brings you out this far？
为什么来这么远的地方？
This little droid.
这个小机器人
I think he's searching for his former master…
我想他正在寻找他以前的主人…
but I've never seen such devotion in a droid before.
我从来没有见过这么忠诚的机器人
He claims to be the property…
他说自己属于…
of an Obi-Wan Kenobi.
一个叫欧比旺·肯诺比的人
Is he a relative of yours？
他是你的亲戚吗？
Do you know who he's talking about？
你知道他说的是谁吗？
Obi-Wan Kenobi？
欧比旺·肯诺比？
Obi-Wan.
欧比旺
Now，that's a name I've not heard in a long time.
这个名字我有很久没有听到过了
A long time.
很久很久
I think my uncle knows him.
我想我的叔叔认识他
He said he was dead.
他说他死了
Oh，he's not dead.
他并没有死
Not yet.
还没有
You know him？
你认识他？
Well，of course I know him。He's me.
哦，我当然认识他，那个人就是我
I haven't gone by the name of Obi-Wan…
我自从你出生前…
since，oh，before you were born.
就不用欧比旺这个名字了
Well，then the droid does belong to you.
看来这个机器人确实属于你
I don't seem to remember ever owning a droid.
我不记得曾经拥有过一个机器人
Very interesting.
非常的有趣
I think we better get indoors.
我想我们最好到室内去
The Sandpeople are easily startled…
沙人很容易被吓跑…
but they'll soon be back，and in greater numbers.
但是他们很快就会回来，而且数量更多
3PO.
3PO
Where am I？I must have taken a bad step.
我在哪里？我刚才一定是踏错地方了
Can you stand？
你能站起来吗？
We've got to get out of here before the Sandpeople return.
我们必须在沙人回来之前离开这里
I don't think I can make it。You go on，Master Luke.
我想我不行的，你走吧，卢克主人
There's no sense in you risking yourself on my account.
你不能为了我威胁到自己的安全
I'm done for.
我真是不中用
No，you're not.
不，你不是的
What kind of talk is that？
说这个算什么？
Quickly。They're on the move.
快点，他们就快来了
No，my father didn't fight in the wars.
不，我的父亲没有打过仗
He was a navigator on a spice freighter.
他是香料货船的领航员
That's what your uncle told you.
这是你叔叔告诉你的
He didn't hold with your father's ideals.
他不赞同你父亲的理想
Thought he should have stayed here…
他想呆在这里…
and not gotten involved.
与世无争
You fought in the Clone Wars？
你曾经参与过克隆人战争？
Yes。I was once a Jedi knight…
是的，我曾是一名绝地武士…
the same as your father.
和你的父亲一样
I wish I'd known him.
我真希望能够了解他
He was the best starpilot in the galaxy…
他曾是银河中最好的星际飞行员…
and a cunning warrior.
是一名睿智的战士
I understand you've become…
我能理解你已经成为…
quite a good pilot yourself.
一名优秀的飞行员
And he was a good friend.
他也曾是我的好朋友
Which reminds me…
这提醒了我
I have something here for you.
有些东西要给你
Your father wanted you to have this…
你的父亲要我把这个给你…
when you were old enough…
当你长大了的时候…
but your uncle wouldn't allow it.
但是你的叔叔是不会允许的
He feared you might follow old Obi-Wan…
他害怕你跟随老欧比旺…
on some damn-fool idealistic crusade…
投身那些愚蠢的理想化的正义运动…
like your father did.
就像你的父亲一样
Sir，if you'll not be needing me…
先生，如果你暂时不需要我
I'll close down for a while.
我先关闭一会
Sure。Go ahead.
好，没问题
What is it？
这是什么？
It's your father's lightsaber.
这是你父亲的光剑
This is the weapon of a Jedi knight.
这是绝地武士的武器
Not as clumsy or random as a blaster.
不像激光枪那样的笨重和不稳定
An elegant weapon for a more civilized age.
是文明时代中的一种优雅的武器
For over a thousand generations…
绝地武士在旧的共和国中
the Jedi knights were the guardians…
是和平与公正的卫士
of peace and justice in the old Republic…
这持续了几千代人
before the dark times…
直到黑暗时代的到来…
before the Empire.
直到帝国的诞生
How did my father die？
我的父亲是怎么死的
A young Jedi named Darth Vader…
一个年轻的名叫达斯·维德的绝地武士…
who was a pupil of mine until he turned to evil…
在他投身黑暗势力之前是我的学生
helped the Empire hunt down and destroy the Jedi knights.
帮助帝国追捕猎杀绝地武士
He betrayed and murdered your father.
他背叛了你的父亲，并且谋杀了他
Now the Jedi are all but extinct.
现在绝地武士几乎灭绝
Vader was seduced by the dark side of the Force.
维德被「原力」的黑暗的一面所引诱
The Force？
「原力」？
The Force is what gives a Jedi his power.
「原力」是绝地武士力量的源泉
It's an energy field created by all living things.
是一种力场，由所有的所有的生物所产生
It surrounds us，penetrates us…
它包围的我们，穿透着我们…
it binds the galaxy together.
他让银河紧密地联系在一起
Now let's see if we can't figure out what you are，my little friend…
现在让我们看看你是怎么一回事，小朋友
and where you come from.
你从哪里来
I saw part of a message he was…
我看过部分信息…
I seem to have found it.
我应该已经找到了
General Kenobi，
肯诺比将军
years ago you served my father in the Clone Wars.
多年前在克隆人战争中，你曾为我的父亲效力
Now he begs you to help him…
现在，他祈求你的帮助
in his struggle against the Empire.
以对付帝国
I regret that I am unable to present my father's request to you in person.
我很抱歉我无法亲自向你呈上我父亲的请求
But my ship has fallen under attack…
我的飞船正在遭受攻击…
and I am afraid my mission to bring you to Alderaan has failed.
恐怕我把你带到奥德兰的计划要失败了
I have placed information vital to the survival of the rebellion…
我有对于反抗军的生死存亡至关重要的信息…
into the memory systems of this R2 unit.
存在了这个R2机器人的内存里
My father will know how to retrieve it.
我的父亲会知道怎么复原的
You must see this droid…
你一定要把这个机器人…
safely delivered to him on Alderaan.
安全的送到奥德兰
This is our most desperate hour.
这是我们最绝望的时刻
Help me，Obi-Wan Kenobi。You're my only hope.
帮帮我，欧比旺·肯诺比，你是我唯一的希望
You must learn the ways of the Force…
你必须要学学使用「原力」的方法
if you're to come with me to Alderaan.
如果你和我去奥德兰的话
Alderaan？I'm not going to Alderaan.
奥德兰？我不去奥德兰
I've got to get home.
我要回家
It's late。I'm in for it as it is.
很晚了，我只能做这么多了
I need your help，Luke。She needs your help.
我需要你的帮助，卢克，她也需要你的帮助
I'm getting too old for this sort of thing.
对于这种事情来说我已经老了
I can't get involved.
我不该卷入的
I've got work to do.
我还有工作要做
It's not that I like the Empire。I hate it…
不是我说喜欢帝国，我憎恨它
but there's nothing I can do about it right now.
但是我现在什么都做不了
It's all such a long way from here.
而且到那里有很远的一段路
That's your uncle talking.
这是你叔叔的口气
My uncle.
我的叔叔
How am I ever gonna explain this？
我该怎么解释这个？
Learn about the Force，Luke.
学习使用「原力」吧，卢克
Look，I can take you as far as Anchorhead.
最远我可以把你送到锚头城
You can get a transport there to Mos Eisley or wherever you're going.
在那里你可以换乘运输机去莫斯艾斯利
或者其他任何你想去的地方
You must do what you feel is right，of course.
当然，你必须做你认为对的事情
Until this battle station is fully operational…
在这个武装空间站正常工作以前
we are vulnerable.
我们都是非常脆弱的
The Rebel Alliance is too well equipped.
叛军联盟的武器非常的精良
They're more dangerous than you realize.
他们比你们想象的更危险
Dangerous to your starfleet，Commander…
对你的舰队来说是危险的，指挥官
not to this battle station.
对这个武装空间站来说可算不上什么
The rebellion will continue to gain support…
叛军会继续获取支持…
in the Imperial Senate…
从帝国参议院那里…
The Imperial Senate will no longer be of any concern to us.
我们再也不用去理会什么帝国参议院了
I have just received word…
我刚刚收到的消息
that the emperor has dissolved the council permanently.
陛下已经永久的解除了议会
The last remnants of the old Republic…
旧共和国的最后一点残余…
have been swept away.
终于被扫除了
That's impossible.
这不可能
How will the emperor maintain control without the bureaucracy？
陛下没有官僚机构怎么统治整个帝国
The regional governors now have direct control…
地方统治者有直接控制权…
over their territories.
所有他们管辖的区域
Fear will keep the local systems in line…
恐惧，将使地方星系秩序井然…
fear of this battle station.
对于这个武装空间站的恐惧
And what of the rebellion？
那么叛军怎么办？
If the rebels have obtained…
如果叛军获取了
a complete technical readout of this station…
这个空间站全面的技术信息
it is possible，however unlikely…
很有可能性，虽然不太可能成功
that they might find a weakness and exploit it.
他们找到这里的一个弱点然后进行利用它
The plans you refer to will soon be back in our hands.
你所提到的这个设计图很快就将落入我们的手中
Any attack made by the rebels against this station…
叛军对于这个空间站任何的攻击…
would be a useless gesture…
都将是毫无意义的行动…
no matter what technical data they've obtained.
无论他们获取到什么技术信息
This station is now the ultimate power in the universe.
这个空间站现在是宇宙中的终极力量
I suggest we use it.
我建议我们利用它
Don't be too proud…
不要过分的骄傲…
of this technological terror you've constructed.
关于你建造的这个技术玩意
The ability to destroy a planet is insignificant…
摧毁一个行星的能力
next to the power of the Force.
和「原力」比起来实在是不算什么
Don't try to frighten us with your sorcerer's ways，Lord Vader.
不要试图用你的巫师技巧来吓唬我，维德勋爵
Your sad devotion to that ancient religion…
你对于那个古老的信仰的忠诚…
hasn't helped you conjure up the stolen data tapes…
没能帮你召唤回丢失的磁带…
or given you clairvoyance enough…
也没有给你足够的洞察力…
to find the rebels' hidden fortre…
去发现叛军的秘密基地…
I find your lack of faith disturbing.
我对你的不敬非常的不满意
Enough of this。Vader，release him.
够了！维德，放开他
As you wish.
听你的
This bickering is pointless.
这种争吵是无意义的
Lord Vader will provide us with the location of the rebel fortress…
维德勋爵在这个空间站正常运作之前…
by the time this station is operational.
会向我们提供叛军基地的地址的
We will then crush the rebellion…
然后我们就去进攻叛军…
with one swift stroke.
要一击致命
It looks like the Sandpeople did this，all right.
看起来是沙人干的
Look。There's gaffi sticks，Bantha tracks.
看，这里有手杖，本莎的脚印
It's just，I've never heard of them…
只是，我从来没有听说…
hitting anything this big before.
他们会攻击这么大的家伙
They didn't…
不是他们干的
but we are meant to think they did.
是有人要让我们相信沙人做的
These tracks are side-by-side.
这些痕迹两边都有的
Sandpeople always ride single file…
沙人总是一列纵队
to hide their numbers.
来隐藏他们的数量
These are the same Jawas that sold us R2 and 3PO.
这和卖给我们R2和3PO的爪哇人人一样
And these blast points，too accurate…
而且，这些爆破点过于精确
for Sandpeople.
对于沙人来说
Only imperial stormtroopers are so precise.
只有帝国的突击队能够这么精确
But why would imperial troops want to slaughter Jawas？
为什么帝国部队要屠杀爪哇人？
If they traced the robots here…
如果他们跟踪机器人到这里…
they may have learned who they sold them to…
他们可能知道机器人被卖到…
and that would lead them back… home！
这样就把他们引到了…家！
Wait，Luke！
等等，卢克！
It's too dangerous！
太危险了
Uncle Owen！
欧文叔叔
Aunt Beru！
贝鲁婶婶
Uncle Owen！
欧文叔叔
And now，Your Highness…
现在，殿下…
we will discuss the location…
让我们来谈谈有关…
of your hidden rebel base.
你们叛军的秘密基地的地址吧
There's nothing you could have done，Luke…
你真么都做不了的，卢克…
had you been there.
如果你在那里的话
You'd have been killed，too…
你也会被杀掉…
and the droids would now be in the hands of the Empire.
而且这两个机器人就落入了帝国的手中
I want to come with you to Alderaan.
我要和你一起去奥德兰
There's nothing for me here now.
我在这里什么都没有了
I want to learn the ways of the Force…
我要学习使用「原力」的方法…
and become a Jedi like my father.
像我父亲一样成为一名绝地武士
Mos Eisley spaceport.
莫斯埃斯利机场
You will never find a more wretched hive of scum and villainy.
你找不到比这里更糟的藏污纳垢的地方了
We must be cautious.
我们必须要小心
How long have you had these droids？
你们拥有这两个机器人多久了
Three or four seasons.
3或4个季度
They're up for sale if you want them.
如果你们需要可以卖给你们
Let me see your identification.
让我看看你们的证件
You don't need to see his identification.
你不需要看他的证件
We don't need to see his identification.
我们不需要看他的证件
These aren't the droids you're looking for.
这些不是你要找的机器人
These aren't the droids we're looking for.
这些不是我们要找的机器人
He can go about his business.
他能去忙自己的事情了
You can go about your business.
你去忙自己的事情吧
Move along.
开走
I can't abide those Jawas。Disgusting creatures！
我不能忍受那些爪哇人人，恶心的生物
Go on，go on.
走开，走开
I can't understand how we got by those troops.
我不知道我们怎么混过那些卫兵的
I thought we were dead.
我以为我们死定了
The Force can have a strong influence…
「原力」对于那些意志不坚定的人
on the weak-minded.
可以产生很强大的影响
Do you really think we're gonna find a pilot here…
你真的认为在这里可以找到一名飞行员
that'll take us to Alderaan？
把我们送到奥德兰吗？
Most of the best freighter pilots are to be found here…
多数优秀的飞行员都在这里出没…
only watch your step.
只是你要小心一点
This place can be a little rough.
这个地方可能有点危险
I'm ready for anything.
我都准备好了
Come along，R2.
来吧，R2
Hey！We don't serve their kind here.
嘿！这玩意我们不接待！
What？
什么？
Your droids，they'll have to wait outside.
你的机器人，他们必须在外面等着
We don't want them here.
他们不让进
Why don't you wait out by the speeder？
不如你们去车上等我们吧
We don't want any trouble.
我们不想惹麻烦
I heartily agree with you，sir.
我同意，先生
Uh…
呃…
I'll have one of those.
给我来一杯
He doesn't like you.
他不喜欢你
I'm sorry.
对不起
I don't like you，either.
我也不喜欢你
You just watch yourself.
你可要小心一点
We're wanted men.
我们可是逃犯
I have the death sentence on 12 systems.
我在12个星系里被判了死刑
I'll be careful.
我会小心的
You'll be dead！
我要杀了你
This little one's not worth the effort.
对这个小家伙不值得这样
Come，let me get you something.
来，我给你买一杯吧
Aah！
啊！
I'm all right.
我没事
Chewbacca here is first mate…
这是秋巴卡，一架飞船的副驾驶…
on a ship that might suit us.
也许能载我们
I don't like the look of this.
我可不喜欢这样
Han Solo。I'm captain of the Millennium Falcon.
汉·索罗，我是千年鹰号的船长
Chewie here tells me you're looking for passage to the Alderaan system.
楚伊告诉我你们需要搭乘去奥德兰星系
Yes，indeed，if it's a fast ship.
是的，没错，如果你的飞船足够块的话
Fast ship？You've never heard of the Millennium Falcon？
足够快？你从来没有听说过千年鹰号？
Should I have？
我应该听过吗？
It's the ship that made the Kessel run in less than 12 parsecs.
不到12秒差就能到达开索
I've outrun imperial starships.
我曾成功逃脱过帝国战舰的追捕
Not the local bulk cruisers，mind you.
提醒你一下，不是什么当地的那些破飞船
I'm talking about the big Corellian ships now.
我说的是大的凯若里战舰
She's fast enough for you，old man.
而且，老头子，对于你来说，足够快了
What's the cargo？
运什么货？
Only passengers… myself，the boy…
只有乘客…我自己，这个孩子…
two droids…
还有两个机器人…
and no questions asked.
还有，不要问任何问题
What is it，some kind of local trouble？
是什么呀？在当地遇到麻烦了？
Let's just say we'd like to avoid…
按我的话说，我们是要躲避…
any imperial entanglements.
帝国军的纠缠
Well，that's the real trick，isn't it？
好，这才是重头戏
And it's gonna cost you something extra.
而且，为了这个我要多收钱的
10，000，all in advance.
10，000，全部提前支付
10，000？
We could almost buy our own ship for that！
我们都可以买自己的飞船了
But who's gonna fly it，kid，you？
但是，谁来给你们开呢？小子，你吗？
You bet I could。I'm not such a bad pilot myself.
我想我可以，我是个不错的飞行员
We don't have to sit here and listen…
我们不要坐在这里听他说…
We can pay you 2，000 now…
我现在可以付给你2，000…
plus 15 when we reach Alderaan.
到奥德兰以后再加15，000
Seventeen，huh？
17，000，对吗？
O.K。You guys got yourselves a ship.
好的，你们找到你们要的船了
We'll leave as soon as you're ready.
你们一准备好我们就出发
Docking Bay 94.
94号停机坪
Ninety-four.
九十四
Looks like somebody's beginning to take an interest in your handiwork.
看起来似乎有人开始对你刚才的那一剑感兴趣了
All right。We'll check it out.
好的，我们去检查一下
17，000！
Those guys must really be desperate.
这些人一定是走投无路了
This could really save my neck.
这些钱可救了我一命
Get back to the ship，get it ready.
回到船上去，做好准备
You'll have to sell your speeder.
你必须把你的车卖了
That's O.K。I'm never coming back to this planet again.
没问题，我以后再也不回这里了
Going somewhere，Solo？
要离开吗，索罗？
Yes，Greedo.
是的，格里多
As a matter of fact，I was just going to see your boss.
事实上，我刚准备去见你的老板
Tell Jabba that I've got his money.
告诉贾巴我现在有钱了
It's too late.
太晚了
You should have paid him when you had the chance.
你已经失去那个机会了
Jabba's put a price on your head so large…
贾巴悬赏了一大笔钱要你的人头…
every bounty hunter in the galaxy will be looking for you.
银河中所有的赏金猎人都在找你
I'm lucky I found you first.
我很幸运第一个找到你
Yeah，but this time I've got the money.
但是，这一次我有钱了
If you give it to me，I might forget I found you.
如果你把钱给我，我可以忘掉这次会面
I don't have it with me.
钱不再我身上
Tell Jabba…
告诉贾巴…
Jabba's through with you.
贾巴看透你了
He has no time for smugglers…
对那些一看到帝国舰队就丢掉货物的走私贩
who drop their shipments at the first sign of an imperial cruiser.
贾巴懒得理他们
Even I get boarded sometimes.
我有时也会失手
Do you think I had a choice？
你认为我有选择吗？
You can tell that to Jabba。He may only take your ship.
你可以自己和贾巴说，他只能拿到你的船了
Over my dead body.
除非我死了
That's the idea.
好主意
I've been looking forward to this for a long time.
我等这一刻很久了
I'll bet you have.
我想你是的
Sorry about the mess.
抱歉添乱了
Her resistance to the mind probe is considerable.
她对于意识探测器的抗拒非常强烈
It'll be some time before we can extract any information from her.
从她那里获取信息需要不少时间
The final checkout is completed.
最终的检测完毕
All systems are operational.
所有的系统都正常运转
What course shall we set？
我们该设定什么轨道？
Perhaps she would respond…
也许她屈服于…
to an alternative form of persuasion.
另一种劝降的方式
What do you mean？
你是什么意思？
I think it is time we demonstrated…
我想现在是时候展示…
the full power of this station.
这个空间站最大火力了
Set your course for Alderaan.
设定轨道为奥德兰
With pleasure.
好的
Lock the door，R2.
把门锁起来，R2
Check this side of the street.
检查一下街道的这边
The door's locked。Move on to the next.
这个门锁了，去下一个
I would much rather have gone with Master Luke…
与和你待在这里相比
than stay here with you.
我更愿意去和卢克主人待在一起
I don't know what all this trouble is about…
我不知道这些麻烦到底是怎么回事…
but I'm sure it must be your fault.
但是我可以肯定这都是你的错
You watch your language.
注意你的语言
All right。Give it to me。I'll take it.
好吧，给我
Look at this.
看看这个
Ever since the XP-38 came out，they just aren't in demand.
自从XP-38问世以后，他们就不太吃香了
It'll be enough.
这些已经够了
Solo！Come out of there，Solo！
索罗！出来吧，索罗！
Right here，Jabba.
我在这里，贾巴
I've been waitin' for you.
我一直在等你
Have you now.
我总算找到你了
You didn't think I was gonna run，did you？
你不会以为我想跑吧，有吗？
Han，my boy，you disappoint me.
汉，我的孩子，你太让我失望了
Why haven't you paid me…
为什么你还不还钱…
and why did you fry poor Greedo？
为什么你杀死了可怜的格里多？
Look，Jabba，next time you want to talk to me，come see me yourself.
贾巴，如下次想找我谈话，你自己来找我
Don't send one of these twerps.
不要派那些废物来
Han，I can't make exceptions.
汉，我不容许例外
What if everyone who smuggled for me…
如果每个帮我运货的人
dropped their cargo at the first sign…
看见帝国的战舰撒腿就跑的话
of an imperial starship？
那我还怎么做生意阿？
It's not good business.
这生意可不好做哦
Look，Jabba，even I get boarded sometimes.
贾巴，就连我也会怕阿
You think I had a choice？
你以为我还有别的选择吗？
But I got a nice，easy charter.
不过我有个很好的提议
I'll pay ya back，plus a little extra.
我会把钱还你的，一分不少还有得多
I just need a little more time.
只是我还需要一点时间
Han，my boy，you're the best.
你是最好的我知道
So，for an extra 20%…
那么就20%吧…
Fifteen，Jabba。Don't push it.
十五，贾巴，最多了
Okay，15%.
好吧，15%
But if you fail me again…
但如果你这次又失败的话…
I'll put a price on your head so big…
我一定会通缉你…
you won't be able to go near a civilized system.
让你永远接近不了有人住的地方
Jabba… you're a wonderful human being.
贾巴，你是我见过最好的人类
Come on！
来吧
If the ship's as fast as he's boasting…
如果这飞船像他讲得那样快的话…
we ought to do well.
我们应该可以成功
What a piece of junk！
这是什么破东西啊！
She'll make.5 past light speed.
他可是光速的5倍哦
She may not look like much…
他也许看起来不怎么样…
but she's got it where it counts，kid.
但是在关键的时候是挺管用的
I've made a lot of special modifications myself.
我自己做过很多的调整
But we're a little rushed，so if you'll just get on board…
但现在时间比较紧，你们如果可以上船的话
we'll get outta here.
我们就要出发了
Hello，sir.
你好，先生
Which way？
往哪里？
All right，men，load your weapons.
把弹药装上
Stop that ship！Blast them！
把那船给我截下来，炸了它！
Chewie，get us out of here！
楚伊，带我们走！
Oh，my。I'd forgotten how much I hate space travel.
天哪，我最讨厌星际旅行了
Looks like an imperial cruiser.
看来是帝国的巡洋舰
Our passengers must be hotter than I thought.
看来那些人是紧咬不放了
Try and hold 'em off.
别让他们追上了
Angle the deflector shields while I make the calculations…
把防护系统调好
for the jump to light speed.
我要做进入光速的准备程序
Stay sharp。There's two more comin' in.
注意了，又有两架
They're gonna try and cut us off.
他们想要截住我们
Why don't you outrun 'em？I thought you said this thing was fast！
你为什么不加速阿？不是说这玩意儿很快吗！
Watch your mouth，kid，or you're gonna find yourself floating home.
注意你说的话，要不你就不要跟着我们
We'll be safe enough…
只要进了外太空
once we make the jump to hyperspace.
我们就安全了
Besides，I know a few maneuvers。We'll lose 'em.
我可以甩掉他们
Here's where the fun begins.
好戏就要开始了
How long before you can make the jump to light speed？
你什么时候才能上光速阿？
It'll take a few moments to get the coordinates from the navicomputer.
我要先从计算机里得到我们坐标
Are you kidding？At the rate they're gaining？
你不回开玩笑吧？他们都快追上来了！
Traveling through hyperspace ain't like dustin' crops，boy！
在外太空航行可不像你想象得那么简单！
Without precise calculations…
如果没有精确的计算…
we'd fly right through a star…
我们可能会撞上一颗恒星
or bounce too close to a supernova…
或是与一颗新行星擦身而过
and that would end your trip real quick，wouldn't it？
这样我们就没得玩了
What's that flashing？
那闪光是什么？
We're losing a deflector shield.
我们的防护网要消失了
Go strap yourselves in.
坐好了
I'm gonna make the jump to light speed.
我们就要进入光速了
We've entered the Alderaan system.
我们就要进入奥德兰了
Governor Tarkin.
塔金行政官
I should have expected…
我早就应该料到了
to find you holding Vader's leash.
是你在控制维德
I recognized your foul stench…
我从一上船
when I was brought on board.
就闻到了你的臭味
Charming to the last.
到现在仍是这么迷人
You don't know how hard I found it…
你不知道我发现下达处决你的命令
signing the order to terminate your life.
心里有多难过
I'm surprised you had the courage…
不过我很高兴
to take the responsibility yourself.
你帮我下了这个决心
Princess Leia，before your execution…
莉娅公主
I would like you to be my guest…
在你被处决之前
at a ceremony that will make this battle station operational.
我希望你能参加我的战斗基地的开幕礼
No star system will dare oppose the emperor now.
再也没有一个星球敢违抗帝国的统治了
The more you tighten your grip，Tarkin…
塔金你越想巩固你的统治
the more star systems will slip through your fingers.
就会有越多的反抗
Not after we demonstrate the power of this station.
但显示了这个基地的威力之后就不会
In a way，you have determined…
你也帮我决定了
the choice of the planet that will be destroyed first.
哪个星球成为他的第一个目标
Since you are reluctant…
既然你不愿意告诉我们
to provide us with the location of the rebel base…
叛军的基地所在
I have chosen to test this station's destructive power…
我只能选择你的故乡奥德兰
on your home planet of Alderaan.
作为我的第一个试验品了
No！Alderaan is peaceful.
不！那是个和平的地方
We have no weapons。You can't possibly…
我们什么武器也没有，你不可以…
You would prefer another target？A military target？
你想要另一个目标吗？军事目标？
Then name the system.
那就说出来啊
I grow tired of asking this，so it will be the last time.
我已经厌倦了，这可是最后一次机会
Where is the rebel base？
叛军基地在哪里？
Dantooine.
塔图因
They're on Dantooine.
他们在塔图因
There。You see，Lord Vader？
你看，维德勋爵
She can be reasonable.
她也是讲道理的
Continue with the operation。You may fire when ready.
继续行动，准备好了就发射
What？
什么？
You're far too trusting.
你太容易相信人了
Dantooine is too remote…
塔图因太远了
to make an effective demonstration，but don't worry.
显示不了他的威力，不过别急
We will deal with your rebel friends soon enough.
我们会慢慢跟你的叛军朋友算账的
No！
不！
Commence primary ignition.
准备发射
Are you all right？What's wrong？
你还好吧？怎么了？
I felt a great disturbance in the Force…
我感觉气不太稳定
as if millions of voices…
好像无数的声音
suddenly cried out in terror…
在恐惧中尖叫
and were suddenly silenced.
然后忽然安静下来了
I fear something terrible has happened.
我想是有什么不好的事发生了
You'd better get on with your exercises.
你继续练习
Well，you can forget your troubles with those imperial slugs.
现在你不用担心那些臭虫了八
I told you I'd outrun them.
我说了我会甩掉他们的
Don't everybody thank me at once.
有人谢我了吗？
Anyway，we should be at Alderaan about 0200 hours.
我们不久就会到奥德兰了
Now be careful，R2.
小心了，R2
Argh！
啊
He made a fair move。Screaming about it can't help you.
这是他自找的，乱叫也不会帮你的
Let him have it。It's not wise to upset a Wookiee.
就让让他吧，惹恼一个伍基人是不明智的
But，sir，nobody worries about upsetting a droid.
但是没人会怕一个猩猩
That's 'cause a droid don't pull people's arms out of their sockets…
那是因为猩猩不会把手臂
when they lose.
从松了的接口里拔出来
Wookiees are known to do that.
伍基人知道怎么做
I see your point，sir.
我明白了
I suggest a new strategy，R2.
我有个新的建议
Let the Wookiee win.
让伍基人赢
Remember，a Jedi can feel the Force flowing through him.
记住了，绝地武士能感觉到气从身体里流过
You mean it controls your actions？
你是说它控制你的行动？
Partially，but it also obeys your commands.
部分的，但他也会服从你的指挥
Hokey religions and ancient weapons are no match…
那些虚伪的宗教和古老的武器
for a good blaster at your side，kid.
并不怎么适合你
You don't believe in the Force，do you？
你并不相信气，对吗？
Kid，I've flown from one side of this galaxy to the other.
小子，我什么地方都去过
I've seen a lot of strange stuff…
也见过不少奇怪的东西
but I've never seen anything to make me believe…
但是我却永远不能相信
there's one all-powerful force controlling everything.
有一种力量能控制一切
There's no mystical energy field controls my destiny.
没有任何奇怪的力量能够控制我的命运的
It's all a lot of simple tricks and nonsense.
这只是些小把戏用来唬人的而已
I suggest you try it again，Luke.
卢克，我建议你再试一次
This time，let go your conscious self…
随心所欲
and act on instinct.
完全不受约束
With the blast shield down，I can't even see.
面罩放下之后我什么都看不见了
How am I supposed to fight？
那我还怎么战斗阿？
Your eyes can deceive you.
你的眼睛会欺骗你的
Don't trust them.
不能相信他们
Stretch out with your feelings.
用你的感觉
You see？You can do it.
瞧，你做的到的
I call it luck.
我觉得是幸运
In my experience，there's no such thing as luck.
我觉得从来就没有幸运
Look，good against remotes is one thing.
也许对静止的物体有用
Good against the living，that's something else.
但对于活动的敌人却又完全不一样了
Looks like we're coming up on Alderaan.
看来我们到奥德兰了
You know，I did feel something.
我感觉到了一些东西
I could almost see the remote.
我几乎就能看见了
That's good.
很好
You've taken your first step…
你已经为你的将来
into a larger world.
迈出了坚实的一步
Yes？
怎么了？
Our scout ships have reached Dantooine.
我们的侦察船到了塔图因
They found the remains of a rebel base…
他们找到了叛军基地
but they estimate that it has been deserted for some time.
但他们估计叛军已经撤离了有一段时间了
They are now conducting an extensive search of the surrounding systems.
他们现在正在做地毯式的搜寻
She lied。She lied to us！
她撒谎！
I told you she would never…
我跟你说了她永远不会
consciously betray the rebellion.
背叛那群叛军的
Terminate her immediately.
马上处决她
Stand by，Chewie。Here we go.
楚伊，准备好了
Cut in the sublight engines.
把引擎关掉
What the…
妈的…
We've come out of hyperspace into a meteor shower.
我们从外太空进入了流星雨区域
Some kind of asteroid collision.
应该是行星撞击产生的吧
It's not on any of the charts.
但是图表上却没有显示
What's going on？
怎么了？
Our position's correct，except no Alderaan.
我们的位置正确无误，但是却没有奥德兰
What do you mean？Where is it？
什么意思？那它去哪儿了？
That's what I'm trying to tell you，kid.
我也想问这个问题
It ain't there。It's been totally blown away.
他不在了，被完整的消灭了
What？How？
什么？怎么做到的？
Destroyed by the Empire.
被帝国毁灭了
The entire starfleet couldn't destroy the whole planet.
就算是整个帝国舰队也不能消灭整颗行星阿
It would take 1，000 ships with more firepower than…
他会需要一千艘战舰的火力…
There's another ship coming in.
又有一艘飞船过来了
Maybe they know what happened.
也许他们知道发生了什么
It's an imperial fighter.
这是帝国的战船
It followed us！
他盯上我们了！
No。It's a short-range fighter.
不，这是艘短程战船
There aren't any bases around here。Where did it come from？
这里没有任何基地，它是从哪里来的？
It sure is leaving in a big hurry.
看起来它走的很急
If they identify us，we're in big trouble.
如果他们认出我们的话就会有大麻烦了
Not if I can help it.
看来我有办法
Chewie，jam its transmissions.
楚伊，扰乱他的通信系统
It would be as well to let it go.
让他走也是个不错的选择
It's too far out of range.
他离我们的射程太远了
Not for long.
不会很久的
A fighter that size couldn't get this deep into space on its own.
那样小的战船是不能独自进入这么深的太空的
He must have gotten lost，been part of a convoy or something.
他应该是从整个战队里走丢了
Well，he ain't gonna be around long enough…
他不会活到
to tell anybody about us.
透露我们的踪迹了
Look at him。He's heading for that small moon.
看，他正飞向那个小的卫星
I think I can get him before he gets there。He's almost in range.
我想我可以在他抵达之前击落他
That's no moon.
这不是卫星
It's a space station.
是一个空间站
It's too big to be a space station.
哪有这么大的空间站阿
I have a very bad feeling about this.
我有一种不祥的预感
Turn the ship around.
掉头
Yeah。I think you're right。Full reverse！
没错，快掉头！
Chewie，lock in the auxiliary power.
楚伊，把备用能源也用上！
Chewie，lock in the auxiliary power！
楚伊，快把备用能源也用上！
Why are we still moving towards it？！
为什么我们还在前进？
We're caught in a tractor beam。It's pulling us in！
我们被吸住了
There's got to be something you can do！
你一定能做什么的！
There's nothing I can do about it，kid.
我什么也不能做，小子
I'm at full power。I'm gonna have to shut down.
已经是全速了，我要关引擎了
They're not gonna get me without a fight.
他们不会那么容易逮到我的
You can't win…
你赢不了的…
but there are alternatives to fighting.
但还有更好的方法
Clear Bay 327.
327号仓位准备
We are opening the magnetic field.
我们将打开磁场
To your stations！
到你们的岗位上去！
Come with me.
跟我来
Close all outboard shields.
把所有防护网关上
Yes？
怎么了？
We've captured a freighter…
我们抓获了一艘货船
entering the remains of the Alderaan system.
他正试图进入奥德兰的废墟
Its markings match those of a ship…
他的外形
that blasted its way out of Mos Eisley.
跟逃离的那艘吻合
They must be trying to return the stolen plans to the princess.
他们应该是准备营救公主的
She may yet be of some use to us.
看来她对我们还有一些作用
Unlock 1，5，7，and 9。Release charge.
1号、5号、7号、9号撤离岗位
316，report to control.
316到指挥室报道
There's no one on board，sir.
船上一个人也没有
According to the log，the crew abandoned ship right after take-off.
根据记录指示，船员在起飞后就遗弃了这艘船
It must be a decoy，sir.
这一定是一个诱饵
Several of the escape pods have been jettisoned.
逃生舱也不见了
Did you find any droids？
找到任何机器人吗？
No，sir.
没有，长官
If there were any on board，they must also have jettisoned.
即使有的话应该也逃生了
Send a scanning crew aboard.
派一个搜索队上去
I want every part of this ship checked.
我要彻彻底底检查这艘船
Yes，sir.
是的，长官
I sense something…
我感觉到了…
a presence I've not felt since…
一种好久没有的感觉
Get me a scanning crew in here on the double.
叫搜查队来
I want every part of this ship checked.
我要检查这艘船
There's no one here.
里面没人
Boy，it's lucky you had these compartments.
还好你有这些小仓位
I use them for smuggling.
那是走私货物用的
I never thought I'd be smuggling myself in 'em.
我从来就没想过我会走私自己
This is ridiculous.
这太荒谬了
Even if I could take off…
即使我能起飞
I'd never get past the tractor beam.
我也过不了那磁场
Leave that to me.
这个由我来解决
Damn fool，I knew that you were gonna say that.
我就知道你这笨蛋会说这个
Who's the more foolish…
你说跟着笨蛋的人
the fool or the fool who follows him？
是不是更笨呢？
The ship's all yours.
现在就把船交给你
If the scanners pick up anything…
如果找到什么的话
report it immediately.
马上报告
All right，let's go.
好的，我们走
Hey，down there！
下面的人！
Could you give us a hand with this？
你们可以帮一下忙吗？
TK-421，why aren't you at your post？
TK-421，为什么你们不在岗位上？
TK-421，do you copy？
TK-421，收到了吗？
Take over。We've got a bad transmitter.
你先接管，信号不太好
I'll see what I can do.
我看看能做什么
Between his howling and your blasting everything in sight…
他的叫声和你的嘈杂声没把他们引来
it's a wonder the whole station doesn't know we're here.
还真是一个奇迹
Bring them on！
让他们来啊
I'd prefer a straight fight to all this sneakin' around.
我宁愿堂堂正正打一架也不要偷偷摸摸的
We've found the computer outlet，sir.
我们已经找到电脑接口了
Plug in。He should be able to interpret the entire imperial network.
插进去，他应该可以破解整个帝国网络
He says he's found the main controls…
他说他找到了
to the power beam that's holding the ship here.
能源系统的主控制
He'll try to make the precise location appear on the monitor.
他会找出准确的位置
The tractor beam is coupled to the main reactor…
磁场跟主反应堆
in seven locations.
一共有7个联系
A power loss at one of the terminals…
任何一处断连
will allow the ship to leave.
都可以让飞船离开
I don't think you boys can help.
我想你们应该帮不上忙
I must go alone.
我要一个人去
Whatever you say.
随便吧
I've done more than I bargained for on this trip already.
我已经仁至义尽了
I want to go with you.
我跟你一起去
Be patient，Luke。Stay and watch over the droids.
要有耐心，卢克
They must be delivered safely…
东西一定要安全的送到
or other star systems will suffer the same fate as Alderaan.
否则其他系统也会有跟奥德兰一样的命运
Your destiny lies along a different path from mine.
你跟我的命运不同
The Force will be with you always.
原力会跟你同在的
You said it，Chewie.
这是你说过的，楚伊
Where did you dig up that old fossil？
你从哪里找来这么一个老顽固？
Ben is a great man.
本是一个很好的人
Yeah，great at getting us into trouble.
没错，好的老是惹来麻烦
I didn't hear you give any ideas.
你也没有给出什么好的建议阿
Well，anything's better than just hangin' around…
任何事都比四处闲逛
waiting for 'em to pick us up.
然后等着被他们发现好
Who do you think…
你以为…
What is it？
怎么了？
I'm afraid I'm not quite sure，sir.
我不是很清楚
He says 「I've found her」 and keeps repeating 「She's here.」
他不停的说我找到她了，她在那里
Well，who… who has he found？
他找到谁了？
Princess Leia.
莉娅公主
The princess？She's here？！
公主？她在这儿？
Princess？
公主？
Where？Where is she？
她在哪里？
Princess？What's going on？
什么公主啊？
Level 5，Detention Block AA-23.
第五层，AA-23号囚室
I'm afraid she's scheduled to be terminated.
好像她马上就要被处决了
Oh，no！
不！
We've got to do something！
我们得做点什么！
What are you talking about？
你在说什么？
The droids belong to her.
机器人是她的
She's the one in the message.
她就是信息里的人
We got to help her.
我们要帮助她
Now look，don't get any funny ideas.
不要胡思乱想了
The old man wants us to wait right here.
那老头让我们在这里呆着
But he didn't know she was here.
但他不知道公主在这里
Just find a way back into that detention block.
找到去囚室的路
I'm not going anywhere.
我什么地方也不会去的
They're going to execute her.
他们要处决她了
Look，a few minutes ago，you said…
刚刚你还说
you didn't want to just wait here to be captured.
你不想在这里等死
Now all you want to do is stay？
现在你又想留下来了？
Marching into the detention area…
但我从来没想过
is not what I had in mind.
要去囚室
But they're gonna kill her！
但他们要杀了她！
Better her than me.
总比杀了我好
She's rich.
她很富有
Rich？
富有？
Mm-hmm。Rich，powerful.
又有钱又有势
Listen，if you were to rescue her，the reward would be…
如果你去救她的话，报酬可是…
What？
什么？
Well，more well than you can imagine.
超出你的想象
I don't know。I can imagine quite a bit.
我的胃口可大了
You'll get it.
你会得到的
I better.
最好这样
You will.
你会的
All right，kid。You better be right about this.
小子，最好你说得没错
All right.
当然
What's your plan？
你的计划是？
Um…
恩
3PO，hand me those binders there，will you？
你可以把那手铐递给我吗？
O.K.
好的
Now… I'm gonna put these on you.
我现在要把它戴在你身上
O.K。Han，you… you put those on.
汉，你来吧
Don't worry，Chewie.
别担心，楚伊
I think I know what he has in mind.
我想我知道他想做什么
Master Luke，sir，pardon me for asking…
卢克主人，请允许我问一下
but what should R2 and I do if we're discovered here？
我跟R2被发现的话该怎么办？
Lock the door.
关上门
And hope they don't have blasters.
希望他们没有炸药吧
That isn't very reassuring.
这听起来并不怎么可靠
517 to scanner control.
517去检查控制室
316，report to control.
316向控制室报道
53 to upper bay door.
53到上层闸门
I can't see a thing in this helmet.
在这个头盔下我什么也看不见
This is not gonna work.
这不会管用的
Why didn't you say so before？
你前面为什么不讲？
I did say so before.
我说了阿
Where are you taking this… thing？
你们要把这东西带去哪里？
Prisoner transfer from Cell Block 1138.
转去1138号囚室
I wasn't notified.
我没有被通知
I'll have to clear it.
让我确认一下
Look out！He's loose！
小心，他的手铐松了！
He'll tear us all apart！
他会把我们都撕成碎片的！
I'll get him！
我来！
Look out！
小心！
We gotta find out which cell this princess of yours is in.
我们得找到是哪间囚室先
Here it is… 2187.
是这间-2187
You go and get her。I'll hold them here.
你去找她，我来缠住他们
Uh… Uh，everything's under control.
一切都控制住了
Situation normal.
情况正常
What happened？
怎么了？
Had a slight weapons malfunction…
武器有点失常
but，uh，everything's perfectly all right now.
现在都已经没问题了
We're fine… We're all fine here now。Thank you.
我们很好，谢谢
How are you？
你怎么了？
We're sending a squad up.
我们正派一个小队过去
Uh，negative，negative！
有情况，有情况！
We have a… a reactor leak here，uh，now.
我们这里的反应堆泄漏
Give us a few minutes to lock it down.
我们需要几分钟来解决
Uh，large leak，very dangerous.
大规模泄漏，很严重
Who is this？What's your operating number？
你是谁？你的号码是多少？
Uh…
恩
Boring conversation anyway.
没什么意义的对话
Luke！We're gonna have company！
卢克，有人要来了！
Aren't you a little short for a stormtrooper？
你会不会太矮了？
Huh？
啊？
Oh，the uniform.
你的制服
I'm Luke Skywalker。I'm here to rescue you.
我叫卢克·天行者，我是来救你的
You're who？
你是谁？
I'm here to rescue you。I've got your R2 unit.
我是来救你的，我有你的R2
I'm here with Ben Kenobi.
我跟本·肯诺比一起来的
Ben Kenobi？！Where is he？
本·肯诺比？他在哪里？
Come on！
快！
He is here.
他在这儿
Obi-Wan Kenobi？
欧比旺·肯诺比？
What makes you think so？
你为什么会这样觉得？
A tremor in the Force.
我的气在振动
The last time I felt it…
上次我感觉到他
was in the presence of my old master.
是在我的老师身边
Surely he must be dead by now.
但他应该已经死了阿
Don't underestimate the Force.
永远不要轻视气
The Jedi are extinct.
绝地武士已经灭绝了
Their fire has gone out of the universe.
他们已经在这个宇宙消失
You，my friend，are all that's left of their religion.
你是他们之中唯一的幸存者了
Yes.
怎么了
We have an emergency alert…
我们有一个警报
in Detention Block AA-23.
在AA-23囚室
The princess？
公主？
Put all sections on alert.
全面警戒
Obi-Wan is here.
欧比旺来了
The Force is with him.
我感觉到他的气了
If you're right…
如果你的判断没错的话
he must not be allowed to escape.
他就不容许逃走
Escape is not his plan.
这不是他的计划
I must face him alone.
我要单独面对他
Get behind me！Get behind me！
到我后面！
Watch your left.
看你的左边
They went down the cell bay.
他们去了闸门
Can't get out that way.
这里行不通
Looks like you managed to cut off our only escape route.
你把我们唯一的去路给堵住了
Maybe you'd like it back in your cell，Your Highness.
看来你是想回到你的囚室了，殿下
C-3PO，C-3PO！
Yes，sir？
怎么了？
Are there any other ways out of the cell bay？
有什么路能走出去吗？
We've been cut off！
我们被堵住了
What was that？I didn't copy.
什么？我听不到
I said all systems have been alerted to your presence，sir.
我说已经全面警戒了
The main entrance seems to be the only way in or out.
只有主通道是开的
All other information on your level is restricted.
你那一层的信息被限制了
Open up in there！
把门打开！
打开门！
Oh，no！
不！
There isn't any other way out！
已经没有路了
I can't hold them off forever！Now what？！
我不能永远挡着他们，现在怎么办？
This is some rescue！
好一个营救！
You came in here，and you didn't have a plan for getting out？
你们进来却没有一个计划出去？
He's the brains，sweetheart！
亲爱的，他才是策划者！
Well，I didn't…
我没有…
What the hell are you doing？
你在干什么？
Somebody has to save our skins.
总的有个办法啊
Into the garbage chute，fly boy.
进垃圾道，快！
Get in there！
快进！
Get in there，you big furry oaf！
快进去你这大家伙！
I don't care what you smell.
我才不管那味道呢
Get in there，and don't worry about it.
快进去，什么也别想
Wonderful girl！
好女孩！
Either I'm going to kill her…
要不我就杀了她
or I'm beginning to like her.
要不我会开始喜欢她
Get in there！
快进去！
Ah！
啊！
The garbage chute was a really wonderful idea.
这么个好主意
What an incredible smell you've discovered！
这是什么味道啊！
Let's get out of here.
快出去
Get away from there.
走开
No，wait！
等一下！
Will you forget it？！I already tried it！
你忘了吗？我已经试过了！
It's magnetically sealed.
这里被磁场封住了
Put that thing away！You're gonna get us all killed！
把那东西拿开！你会杀了我们的！
Absolutely，Your Worship.
没错，我的神！
Look，I had everything under control till you led us down here！
一切都很好直至你把我们带进来！
Ya know，it's not gonna take 'em long…
他们不会需要多久
to figure out what happened to us！
来知道我们去哪儿的！
It could be worse.
没什么比这个更糟的了
It's worse.
没错
There's something alive in here.
这里有生物
That's your imagination.
那是你的幻觉
Something just moved past my leg.
有东西从我的腿边经过
Look！Did you see that？
你看见了吗？
What？
什么？
Kid！
小子！
Luke！
卢克！
Luke！Luke，grab hold of this！
卢克，抓住这个！
Blast it！My gun's jammed.
妈的，我的枪被卡住了
Where？
哪儿？
Anywhere！
随便！
Luke，Luke！
卢克！
Help him！
快帮他！
What happened？
怎么了？
I don't know.
我不知道
It just let go of me and disappeared.
他们忽然松开我走了
I got a bad feeling about this.
我有不祥的预感
The walls are moving！
墙在动！
Don't just stand there！
别站着不动！
Try and brace it with something.
用什么东西顶住
Help me！
快帮我！
Wait a minute！
等一下
3PO！
Come in，3PO！
快点3PO！
3PO！
Where could he be？
它去哪儿了？
Take over。See to him.
到位，快找
Look，there.
在这儿
They're madmen.
他们疯了
They're heading for the prison level.
他们去监狱那一层了
If you hurry，you might catch them.
如果够快的话也许还能抓到他们
Follow me.
跟我走
You stand guard.
你在这里守着
Come on.
快
Oh！
哦！
All this excitement has overrun the circuits in my counterpart here.
我的朋友出了一点故障
If you don't mind，I'd like to take him down to maintenance.
如果你不介意我想带他去维修
All right.
好
3PO！
Come in，3PO！
快，3PO！
3PO！
Get on top！
到上面去！
I can't.
我上不去
Where could he be？！3PO！
他跑去哪里？3PO
3PO，will you come in！
3PO，你答话！
They aren't here.
他们不在这里
Something must have happened to them.
一定出事了
See if they've been captured.
看他们是否被抓了
Hurry.
快点！
One thing's for sure…
有件事可确定
we're all gonna be a lot thinner.
我们都要变瘦了
Get on top of it.
到上面去
I'm trying.
我在努力了
Thank goodness they haven't found them.
谢天谢地！帝国军还没找到他们
Where could they be？
他们去哪里了呢？
「Use the comlink」？
用通话器？
Oh，my。I forgot。I turned it off.
我忘了我把它关了
Are you there，sir？
你在吗？先生？
3PO！
We've had some problems.
我们发生了点问题…
Will you shut up and listen to me？！
你闭嘴听我说好吗？
Shut down all the garbage mashers on the detention level，will ya？！
关闭囚犯区的垃圾库电力，好吗？！
Do you copy！？
你听到了吗？
Shut down all the garbage mashers on the detention level！
把囚犯区的垃圾库电力都关闭！
No！Shut them all down。Hurry！
没错！全部关闭，快呀！
What？
什么？
Ha ha！
哈哈！
Listen to them。They're dying，R2！
你听他们的叫声，他们就要死了，R2！
Curse my metal body！
天咒我吧！
I wasn't fast enough。It's all my fault！My poor master.
我的动作不够快，全是我的错，我可怜的主人
We're all right！You did great！
我们没事了！太棒了，你做的太好了
Hey！Open the pressure maintenance hatch…
打开这里的压力门
on unit number… Where are we？
我们在哪里？
3263827！
我们在32-63-827下面
If we can just avoid any more female advice…
只要避免再有女性建议，
we ought to be able to get outta here.
我们就能离开这儿
Well，let's get moving.
我们快走吧！
Where are you going？
你去那儿？
No，wait！They'll hear！
等等！他们会听到
Come here，you big coward.
过来！你这懦夫
Chewie，come here.
楚伊，过来
Listen…
听着！
I don't know who you are or where you came from…
我不知你是谁？从何而来
but from now on，you do as I tell you，OK？
从现在开始，照我的话作，好吗？
Look，Your Worshipfulness…
听着！殿下…
let's get one thing straight.
我们先弄清楚
I take orders from just one person… me.
我只听命于一个人，我！
It's a wonder you're still alive.
你还活着真是奇迹
Will somebody get this big walking carpet out of my way？
谁来搬开这活动地板？
No reward is worth this.
没有奖赏值得我经受这一切
Give me regular reports，please.
请把我例行的报告给我
Right.
好的
Do you know what's going on？
你知道是怎么回事吗？
Maybe it's another drill.
也许又是一次演习吧
You seen that new VT-16？
看到那个新的VT-16了吗？
Yeah。Some of the other guys were telling me about it.
听别人说了
They say it's… it's quite a thing to see…
他们说它值得一看
What was that？
那是什么？
Ah，it's nothing。Outgassing.
没什么正在排气
Don't worry about it.
不要担心
There she is.
船就在那边了
C-3PO？Do you copy？
C-3PO！你听到吗？
Yes，sir.
是的！
- Are you safe？- For the moment.
- 你安全吗？- 目前是
We're in the main hangar across from the ship.
我们在主机棚，飞船那边
We're right above you。Stand by.
我们就在你上面！待命
You came in that thing？
你的船？
You're braver than I thought.
你比我想的还勇敢
Nice！Come on.
很好！走吧
It's them！
是他们！
Blast them！
开火！
Get back to the ship！
回船去
Where are you going？Come back！
你去哪里？回来！
He certainly has courage.
他的确有勇气！
What good will it do us…
如果他这样丢掉自己的性命…
if he gets himself killed？Come on.
对我们会有什么好处呢？来
I think we took a wrong turn.
我们转弯转错了
There's no lock.
没有锁
That oughta hold them for a while.
这应让能挡住他们一阵
Quick！We've got to get across.
快！我们得过去
Find the controls that extend the bridge.
找出控制器把桥延伸出去
I think I just blasted it.
我刚把它打坏
They're coming through！
但他们就要过来了呀！
Here，hold this.
拿着！
Here they come.
他们来了
For luck.
好运
We think they may be splitting up.
他们可能单独行动
They may be on Level 5 and 6 now，sir.
已经到了5楼或6楼
Where could they be？
他们人呢？
Close the blast doors！
把门关上！
Open the blast doors！Open the blast doors！
把门打开！把门打开！
I've been waiting for you，Obi-Wan.
我在等你！欧比旺！
We meet again at last.
我们终于再度见面
The circle is now complete.
循环完成
When I left you，I was but the learner.
我离开你时是学生
Now I am the master.
如今我是大师了
Only a master of evil，Darth.
邪恶大师，达斯·维德
Your powers are weak，old man.
你的力量太弱了，老头子
You can't win，Darth.
你赢不了的，达斯·维德
If you strike me down…
如果你将我击倒…
I shall become more powerful than you can possibly imagine.
我会比你所想像的还要有力
You should not have come back.
你不该回来
Didn't we just leave this party？
我们快离开这里？
What kept you？
你们被什么耽误了？
We，uh，ran into some old friends.
我们遇到些老朋友
The ship all right？
船没事吧？
It seems OK，if we can get to it.
看上去很好，只要我们能上得去
I just hope the old man got the tractor beam out of commission.
希望老头消除了磁力牵引光束
Look！
看！
Come on，R2，we're going.
走吧！R2，我们要走了
Now's our chance！Go！
这是我们的机会，快走！
Ben？
本？
No！
不！
Come on！
快来呀！
Luke，it's too late！
卢克，已经太迟了！
Blast the door，kid！
把开关打坏！
Run，Luke，run！
快跑！卢克！
I hope that old man got that tractor beam out of commission…
希望老头破坏了磁力牵引光束…
or this is gonna be a real short trip。O.K。Hit it！
我们就能迅速离去，好！发动！
We're coming up on their sentry ships.
如果有他们的哨兵飞船
Hold them off.
挡住它们
Angle the deflector shields while I charge up the main guns.
升起防护网，将主要炮管装满
I can't believe he's gone.
我无法相信他已死了
There wasn't anything you could have done.
你也无能为力
Come on，buddy。We're not out of this yet.
来吧！这件事还未完呢
You in，kid？OK，stay sharp.
你进来了吗？好！保持警觉
Here they come.
他们来了！
They're coming in too fast！
他们来得太快！
We've lost the lateral controls！
我们的侧面失去控制！
Don't worry。She'll hold together.
不要担心！这船能够撑住
Hear me，baby？Hold together.
宝贝，稳住！
Got him！I got him！
我打中它了！太好了
Great，kid！Don't get cocky.
不要就此自满
There's still two more of them out there！
外面还有2个！
That's it！We did it！
这就对了！我们成功了！
We did it！
我们成功了！
Help！I think I'm melting！This is all your fault！
救命！我觉得我好像在融化！这都是你的错！
Are they away？
他们走远了吗？
They've just made the jump into hyperspace.
他们刚冲进超太空
You're sure the homing beacon is secure aboard their ship？
你确信追踪器装好了？
I'm taking an awful risk，Vader.
我这可是冒很大的险
This had better work.
这招最好有效
Not a bad bit of rescuing，huh？
还算成功的援救，是吧？
You know，sometimes I amaze even myself.
有时连我自己也感惊奇
That doesn't sound too hard.
这并不难呀
They let us go.
他们是故意让我们走
It's the only explanation for the ease of our escape.
这是我们能轻易逃离的唯一解释
Easy？You call that easy？
轻易，你说这样是轻易？
They're tracking us.
他们追踪我们
Not this ship，sister.
不可能对这条船的
At least the information in R2 is still intact.
起码R2身上的情报未被破坏
What's so important？What's he carrying？
什么情报如此重要？它带着什么？
The technical readouts of that battle station.
那个战斗站的结构图
I only hope that when the data's analyzed…
我只希望等我们分析时…
a weakness can be found.
能找出它的弱点
It's not over yet.
这件事还未结束呢
It is for me，sister.
对我可是结束了
Look，I ain't in this for your revolution…
我参与此事不是为了你的革命…
and I'm not in it for you，Princess.
也不是为了你
I expect to be well paid.
我是期望有优厚的报酬
I'm in it for the money.
我是为钱参与此事
You needn't worry about your reward.
你不用担心你的报酬
If money is all that you love…
如果你就只爱钱…
then that's what you'll receive.
那就是你会获得的
Your friend is quite a mercenary.
你的朋友，好个佣兵
I wonder if he really cares about anything…
我看他不关心任何事…
or anybody.
或任何人
I care.
我关心呀！
So…
所以…
what do you think of her，Han？
你觉得她如何？
I'm trying not to，kid.
我尽量不去想她，孩子
Good.
很好
Still，she's got a lot of spirit.
不过我认为她很有胆识
I don't know。What do you think？
我不知道你说呢？
You think a princess and a guy like me…
公主配我这样的人，你觉得如何…
No！
不好！
You're safe.
你获救了
When we heard about Alderaan…
当我们听到奥德兰的消息时…
we feared the worst.
我们最害怕
We have no time for sorrows，Commander.
我们没时间伤心了，指挥官
You must use the information in this R2 unit…
你必须使用R2身上的情况…
to help plan the attack.
来策划攻击行动
It's our only hope.
那是我们唯一的希望
Yes.
是的
We're approaching the planet Yavin.
我们正接近耶比星球
The rebel base is on a moon on the far side.
叛军基地在另一头的卫星上
We are preparing to orbit the planet.
我们打算绕耶比星飞行
The battle station is heavily shielded…
帝国战斗站严密的防卫…
and carries a firepower…
具有的火力…
greater than half the starfleet.
比半个星际舰队还要强
Its defenses are designed around a direct large-scale assault.
它的防卫措施是根据大型直接的攻击而设计
A small，one-man fighter should be able to penetrate the outer defense.
单人战斗机应能穿越外层的防卫
Pardon me for asking，sir…
请问，首长…
but what good are snub fighters going to be against that？
我们小型战斗机对抗它又有何用？
The Empire doesn't consider a small，one-man fighter…
帝国认为小型单人机…
to be any threat…
不具威胁…
or they'd have a tighter defense.
不然他们会有更严密的防卫系统
An analysis of the plans provided by Princess Leia…
莉娅公主所提供的敌军分析图…
has demonstrated a weakness in the battle station.
显示他们的基地有个弱点
The approach will not be easy.
要接近并不容易
You're required to maneuver straight down this trench…
你们必须低飞到这个狭沟…
and skim the surface to this point.
然后沿着狭沟而行，直到这一点
The target area is only 2 meters wide.
攻击目标区仅两米宽
It's a small thermal exhaust port…
是个反应炉排气口…
right below the main port.
就在主排气口的下方
The shaft leads directly to the reactor system.
孔道直通反应炉系统
A precise hit will start a chain reaction…
正中目标能引起连锁反应…
which should destroy the station.
毁灭帝国军战斗站
Only a precise hit will set up a chain reaction.
只有正中目标才能引起连锁反应
The shaft is ray-shielded…
此排气口有防击保护层…
so you'll have to use proton torpedoes.
所以你们必须使用质子弹
That's impossible，even for a computer.
这连电脑也办不到
It's not impossible.
并非不可能的
I used to bull's-eye womp rats in my T-16 back home.
我以前在家乡常用T-16击中我的面包中心点
They're not much bigger than 2 meters.
那还没有两米宽
Then man your ships，and may the Force be with you.
上你们的宇宙飞船吧！愿原力与你们同在！
Orbiting the planet at maximum velocity.
全速环绕耶比星球
The moon with the rebel base…
叛军基地所在的卫星…
will be in range in 30 minutes.
将在30分钟内进入射程
This will be a day long remembered.
这将是一个值得纪念的日子
It has seen the end of Kenobi…
我们己经见到欧比旺的末日…
and will soon see the end of the rebellion.
很快也要见到叛军的末日
All flight crews，man your stations.
全体飞行队员就位
So… you got your reward and you're just leaving，then？
你领到你的赏金，你就要走了？
That's right。Yeah.
是的
I got some old debts I got to pay off with this stuff.
我还有债要还
And even if I didn't…
就算没有债要还…
you don't think I'd be fool enough to stick around here，do ya？
你想我会傻到留下来？
Why don't you come with us？
为何不跟我们走？
You're pretty good in a fight。We could use ya.
你能打仗，我用得上你
Come on。Why don't you take a look around？
好了！你何不看看四周？
You know what's about to happen…
你知道即将发生什么事？
what they're up against.
知道他们要对抗谁？
They could use a good pilot like you.
他们用得上你这样的好飞行员
You're turning your back on them.
你这样是背弃他们
What good's a reward if you ain't around to use it？
人死了，赏金有什么用？
Besides，attacking that battle station…
况且攻击帝国军战斗站…
ain't my idea of courage.
并非我认为的勇气之举
It's more like… suicide.
我看更像…自杀
All right.
好吧！
Take care of yourself，Han.
保重你自己
I guess that's what you're best at，isn't it？
我想那是你最拿手的事，对吧？
Hey，Luke.
卢克
May the Force be with you.
愿原力与你同在
What are you looking at？
你看个什么劲儿？
I know what I'm doing.
我知道我在作什么
All pilots to your stations.
所有飞行员就位
What's wrong？
怎么了？
Oh，it's Han.
是汉！
I don't know。I really thought he'd change his mind.
我不知道，我以为他改变主意了
He's got to follow his own path.
他必须走他自己的路
No one can choose it for him.
别人没办法替他选择
I only wish Ben were here.
我真希望本也在这儿
Open main launch tubes.
打开飞行管道
Main launch tubes opening，sir.
Hey，Luke！
嘿，卢克！
Biggs！
比格斯！
I don't believe it。How are you？
你好吗？
Great.
很好
Hey，coming up？
上去吗？
I'll be right up there with you…
我马上去与你会合…
and have I got stories to tell you.
有很多话要告诉你
Are you sure you can handle this ship？
你有把握能应付这种机型吗？
Sir，Luke is the best bush pilot in the outer-rim territories.
首长，路克是外太空中最厉害的飞行员
You'll do all right.
你应该能胜任
Thank you，sir。I'll try.
谢谢，我会尽力的
I gotta get aboard.
该上机了
We'll hear all your stories when we get back，all right？
回程再听你的故事好了，好吗？
All right.
好的
Hey，Biggs.
比格斯
I told you I'd make it someday.
告诉过你我会成功的
It'll be like old times，Luke.
就像往常一样，卢克
They'll never stop us.
没人挡的住我们
Hey，this R2 unit of yours seems a bit beat up.
你的R2好像很旧了
You want a new one？
要换个新吗？
Not on your life.
才不呢！
That little droid and I have been through a lot together.
我和这个小机器人合作很久
You OK，R2？
你还好吗？R2
Good.
好！
Gold squadron，begin take-off procedure.
金色编队，准备起飞
Hang on tight，R2。You've got to come back.
稳住！R2，你必须回来
You wouldn't want my life to get boring，would you？
你不想让我的生活无聊吧
Luke，the Force will be with you.
卢克，愿原力与你同在！
Standby alert.
提高警觉
Death Star approaching.
死亡星球接近
Estimated time to firing range，15 minutes.
预计15分钟内到达射程
All wings report in.
所有飞行员向我报告
Red 10 standing by.
红色10号待命！
Red Seven standing by.
红色7号待命！
Red Three standing by.
红色3号待命！
Red Six standing by.
红色6号待命！
Red Nine standing by.
红色9号待命！
Red Two standing by.
红色2号待命！
Red 11 standing by.
红色11号待命！
Red Five standing by.
红色5号待命！
Lock S-foils in attack position.
进入攻击队形
We're passing through the magnetic field.
我们正通过磁场
Hold tight.
跟紧！
Switch your deflectors on。Double front.
设定防护装置，双层前护网
Look at the size of that thing！
这东西如此庞大！
Cut the chatter，Red Two。Accelerate to attack speed.
关闭快门！红色2号，加速至攻击速度
This is it，boys.
这就是了，小伙子们！
Red Leader，this is Gold Leader.
红色队长！这里是金色队长
I copy，Gold Leader.
正听着，金色队长
We're starting for the target shaft now.
我要朝目标口前进
We're in position.
我们已经就位
I'm going to cut across the axis…
我要冲进去…
and try and draw their fire.
吸引他们的火力
Heavy fire，boss，23 degrees.
强火力，在23度
I see it。Stay low.
看到了，保持低飞
This is Red Five。I'm going in.
我是红色5号，我要进去了
Luke，pull up！
卢克，拉起来！
Are you all right？
你还好吗？
I got a little cooked，but I'm O.K.
机身擦到一点但没事
We count 30 rebel ships，Lord Vader…
有30架叛军的战斗机，维德勋爵…
but they're so small…
但他们好小…
they're evading our turbolasers.
穿越我们的镭射光
We'll have to destroy them ship to ship.
我们得一架一架毁掉他们
Get the crews to their fighters.
让飞行员上战斗机
Watch yourself。There's a lot of fire coming…
全体注意！
from the right side of that deflection tower.
右边的炮塔，攻击猛烈！
I'm on it.
我来
I'm going in。Cover me，Porkins.
掩护我，福金
I'm right with you，Red Three.
我跟着你，红色3号
I've got a problem here.
我有个问题
Eject.
退出！
I can hold it.
我没事
Pull up！
拉起来！
No，I'm all…
不！
The rebel base will be in firing range…
叛军基地…
in seven minutes.
在7分钟内进入射程
Luke，trust your feelings.
卢克，信任你的感觉
Squad leaders，we've picked up a new group of signals.
飞行领队，我们收到新的信号
Enemy fighters coming your way.
敌军战斗机朝你的方向飞去
My scope's negative。I don't see anything.
我的扫描器上没有显示，我什么也没看到
Pick up your visual scanning.
用你的目视扫描
Here they come.
他们来了！
Watch it。You've got one on your tail.
小心了！有一个在你尾巴后面
I'm hit！
击中了！
You've picked one up！Watch it！
已击中一架，小心！
I can't see it！
我看不到
He's on me tight。I can't shake him！
跟得很紧，无法摔掉它！
I'll be right there.
我马上就来了
Several fighters have broken off…
有几个战斗机脱离主队…
from the main group。Come with me.
来掩护我
Fall in！Fall in！
集合！集合！
Watch your back，Luke.
小心你的后面，卢克
Watch your back.
小心你的后面
Fighters above you，coming in.
敌机逼近
I'm hit，but not bad.
我被击中，但还好
R2，see what you can do with it.
R2，看你能不能想办法
Hang on back there.
等着
Red Six，can you see Red Five？
红色6号，你看到红色5号吗？
There's a heavy fire zone.
炮火还是很猛
Red Five，where are you？
红色5号，你在哪里？
I can't shake him！
我摆脱不了他！
I'm on him，Luke。Hold on.
稳住！卢克
Blast it，Biggs！Where are you？
比格斯！你在哪里？
Thanks，Wedge.
谢了，威治
Good shooting，Wedge。Red Leader…
打的好！
this is Gold Leader.
这里是金色队长
We're starting our attack run.
我们要开始我们的行动
I copy，Gold Leader。Move into position.
知道了，队长，马上就位
Stay in attack formation.
攻击队形
The exhaust port is marked and locked in.
锁定排气孔
Switch all power…
把动力转至…
to front deflector screen.
把所有动力转到前面防弹
Switch all power…
把动力转至…
to front deflector screen.
把所有动力转到前面防弹
How many guns do you think，Gold Five？
你看有多少火炮，金色5号？
Say about 20 guns…
大约20门
some on the surface，some on the towers.
有些在表面，有些在塔上
Death Star will be in range in five minutes.
死亡星球5分钟内进入射程
Switch to targeting computer.
启动瞄准电脑
Computer locked。Getting a signal.
电脑收到讯号
The guns！They've stopped！
大炮…停止发射了
Stabilize your rear deflectors.
稳住你们的尾部变流器
Watch for enemy fighters.
小心敌军战斗机
They're coming in！Three marks at 210.
他们来了！有3架在2点10分位置
I'll take them myself。Cover me.
在我的侧位，掩护我
Yes，sir.
是的
It's no good。I can't maneuver.
我没办法行动
Stay on target.
紧跟目标
We're too close.
我们太近了
Stay on target.
紧跟目标
Loosen up！
离远一点！
Gold Five to Red Leader，lost Tiree，lost Hutch.
金色呼叫红色队长，失去两架战机
I copy，Gold Leader.
知道了，金色队长
They came from behind.
从后面来的
We've analyzed their attack，sir…
已分析他们的攻击
and there is a danger.
有危险
Should I have your ship standing by？
要我准备好你的宇宙飞船吗？
Evacuate in our moment of triumph？
在我们胜利的时刻撤退？
I think you overestimate their chances.
我看你高估他们的机会了
Rebel base，three minutes and closing.
叛军基地3分钟，接近中
Red boys，this is Red Leader.
红色战斗机，这里是红色队长
Rendezvous at mark 6.1.
61位置会合
This is Red Two flying toward you.
这里是红色2号，向你飞来
Red Three standing by.
红色3号待命
Red Leader，this is Base One.
红色队长，这里是一号基地
Keep half your group out of range…
保留一半人马…
for the next run.
准备展开下一波行动
Copy，Base One。Luke，take Red Two and Three.
知道了，一号基地路克，红色2号及3号
Hold up here and wait for my signal to start your run.
在这儿等我的讯号展开你们的行动
This is it！
这就是了！
We should be able to see it by now.
我们现在应该已经看到
Keep your eyes open for those fighters.
注意那些战斗机
There's too much interference.
太多干扰
Red Five，can you see them from where you are？
红色5号，你能看到敌军战斗机吗？
No sign of any… Wait。Coming in.35.
什么也没看…慢着！3点5分方向
I see them.
我看到了
I'm in range.
进入射程
Target's coming up.
目标快要到了
Just hold them off for a few seconds.
只要挡住他们几秒钟
Close up formation.
排成对形
Almost there.
快到了
You'd better let her loose。They're right behind me.
我摆脱不掉他们，他们就在我后面
Almost there.
就快到了
I can't hold them.
我挡不住他们
It's away！
发射了！
It's a hit！
击中了吗？
Negative，negative。It didn't go in.
没中！没中！没进去
It just impacted on the surface.
只在表面爆炸
Red Leader，we're right above you.
红色队长，我们就在你上面
Turn to.05。We'll cover for you.
转向05方向，我会掩护你
Stay there。I just lost my starboard engine.
我刚损失右舷引擎
Get set up for your attack run.
展开你的攻击行动
Rebel base，one minute and closing.
叛军基地，一分钟，继续接近
Biggs，Wedge，let's close it up.
比格斯、威治，我们向目标接近
We're going in full throttle.
我们要全力冲进去
That ought to keep those fighters off our back.
你替我挡住那些战斗机
Right with you，boss.
紧跟着你
Luke，at that speed，will you be able to pull out in time？
你的速度能及时击中吗？
It'll be just like Beggars Canyon back home.
没问题，顺顺利利地
We'll stay back far enough to cover you.
我们在你后面，掩护你
My scope shows the tower…
我看得到塔…
but I can't see the exhaust port.
但看不到排气口
Are you sure the computer can hit it？
你确信电脑能击中吗？
Watch yourself。Increase speed，full throttle.
你自己要小心，要加速前速
What about that tower？
炮塔呢？
You worry about those fighters！
你管敌机！
I'll worry about the tower！
我来管炮塔！
R2，that stabilizer's broken loose again.
R2，稳定器又松了
See if you can't lock it down.
你把它固定好吗？
Fighters coming in.3.
敌机来了，3点方向
I'm hit！I can't stay with you！
我被击中，我不能跟你了
Get clear，Wedge。You can't do any more good back there.
退开，威治，你在后面也帮不了忙
Sorry.
抱歉！
Let him go。Stay on the leader.
让他走！跟着领队战斗机
Hurry，Luke。They're coming in much faster this time.
快点！卢克，这次他们速度更快
We can't hold them.
我们挡不住他们
R2，try and increase the power.
R2，加速！
Hurry up，Luke！
快点！卢克！
Quick！Quick！
快点！快点！
Rebel base，30 seconds and closing.
叛军基地，30秒，继续接近
I'm on the leader.
我来对付领队
Hang on，R2.
支持下去！R2
Use the Force，Luke.
使用宇宙之原力，卢克
Let go，Luke.
放手去作！
The Force is strong with this one.
这架原力很强烈
Luke，trust me.
卢克！相信我
His computer's off.
他的电脑关掉了
Luke，you switched off your targeting computer！
路克！你关掉瞄准的电脑！
What's wrong？
怎么回事？
Nothing。I'm all right.
没事！我很好
I've lost R2！
我损失了R2！
The Death Star has cleared the planet.
星球受到威胁
Rebel base in range.
叛军基地在射程内
You may fire when ready.
准备好了就射击
Commence primary ignition.
开始第一次点火！
I have you now.
我逮到你了！
What？
什么？
Yahoo！
喔！！
Look out！
小心！
You're all clear，kid！Now let's blow this thing and go home！
没障碍了，小子，现在快炸掉目标，我们回家
Stand by.
预备！
Great shot，kid！
射得好，小子！
That was one in a million！
百里挑一
Remember，the Force will be with you always.
记着！原力将与你同在…永远
Luke！
卢克！
Hey！Hey！
嘿！嘿！
I knew you'd come back。I just knew it.
我就知道你会回来！我就知道
Well，I wasn't going to let you get all the credit…
我才不让你独享功劳…
and take all the reward.
拿走所有赏金
Hey，I knew there was more to you than money.
我就知道你不是只看重钱
Oh，no！
糟了！
Oh，my。R2，can you hear me？
R2，你能听到我说话吗？说话呀！
Say something。You can repair him，can't you？
说点什么，你能修理他吧
We'll get to work on him right away.
我们马上着手
You must repair him.
你们一定把他修好
Sir，if any of my circuits or gears will help…
如果我有什么电路能帮助…
I'll gladly donate them.
我很乐意提供
He'll be all right.
他会修复的